Dewan M.I. Mukto

dm@mux8.com | LinkedIn: dewanmukto | GitHub: dwmk | dewanmukto.github.io

About

Dewan M.I. Mukto is a multipotentialite interested in maximizing profits and efficiency under the influence of his ENFP-T MBTI personality type. He is notable for his contributions to the fields of art, literature, science, and technology. Since 2014, Dewan Mukto has been active in creating various types of content and tasks including videos and vlogs, music production, graphic designing, UI and UX designing, programming, web development, app development, game development, writing novels, poetry and books, 3D animation, shader scripting, fashion and merch design, digital marketing, project management, motivational speaking, customer retention, entrepreneurship, brand building, academic teaching and training, and research upon the fields of AI, mathematics, economics, and psychology.

Education

BRAC University, Dhaka, Bangladesh
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (Credit Transferred)

Memorial University of Newfoundland and Labrador, St. John's, Canada
BSc in Computer Science, CGPA: 3.06/4.00, 83/120 Credits

Anandaniketan School, Sylhet, Bangladesh
Pearson Edexcel IGCSE: 9 in Physics, 9 in Chemistry, 9 in Biology, 9 in Mathematics, 9 in ICT, 9 in English Language,
9 in Bengali Language, 9 in Further Pure Mathematics
IAS: A in Physics, A in Chemistry, A in Mathematics, A in Further Mathematics
June 2020
IA2: A in Mathematics, B in Physics, C in Chemistry
June 2024

Experience

Experience	
Mux AI, Remote, Bangladesh	Jul 2023–Present
Web Developer, Software Developer, Marketing Strategist, Graphic Designer, UI/	UX Designer
Sherwin-Williams, St. John's, Canada	Jul 2022–Jun 2023
Sales Associate	
Jungle Jim's Eatery, St. John's, Canada	$\operatorname{Jun}\ 2022\text{-}\operatorname{Aug}\ 2022$
Kitchen Helper	
Mark's, St. John's, Canada O	ct 2021–Feb 2022, Jul 2022–Aug 2022
Sales Associate	
Dewan IELTS, Remote, Bangladesh	$\mathrm{Jan}\ 2021\text{-}\mathrm{Feb}\ 2022$
IELTS Trainer	
Mux Anime Studios, Remote, Bangladesh	Nov 2019–Feb 2022
Director, Animator, Marketing Strategist, Recruiter	
Pathantula Govt Primary School, Sylhet, Bangladesh	Apr 2018–Nov 2018
English Language Teacher	

Skills

Programming: Python, Java, C, Fortran, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, OpenGL, Lua, Kotlin, NextJS, Vite, Selenium

Technical: Web SaaS Development, UI/UX Design, Figma, Git, Linux, SEO, Image/Video Editing, Microsoft Office, Canva, WordPress, Wix, Webflow, Bubble.io

Business: Brand Marketing, Digital Marketing, Project Management, Product Design, Copywriting, Customer Engagement, Lead Generation

Passive: Leadership, Creativity, Problem Solving, Teaching, Motivational Speaking, Entrepreneurship, Statistical Analysis

Publications

In The Wildest Dimensions (written 2023, published 2024): Psychological thriller novel, ISBN: 9798880533060 Synaesthetic Symphonies (written 2019, published 2023): Aesthetic poetry anthology, ISBN: 9781446750544 IELTS Guide (written 2019, published 2023): Guide for IELTS preparation, ISBN: 9798210806888 Dead Man Alive (written 2017, published 2023): Horror/paranormal novella, ISBN: 9781446740972 Cooper Black (written 2016, published 2022): Action/science-fiction novel, ISBN: 9798880654475

Achievements

National Builders of Tomorrow Award, The Daily Star Awards, 2020

Pearson Edexcel Higher Achievers' Award, 2020

IELTS Overall Score: 8.5, 2019

Bronze Award, Duke of Edinburgh Awards, 2019

National Rounder (1st Rank in Sylhet), 2nd English Olympiad, 2018

National Rounder, 13th Bangladesh Astro-Olympiad, 2018

National Rounder, 1st English Olympiad, Jan 2017

Honorable Mention, 9th Bangladesh Physics Olympiad, 2019

3rd Prize, CAM SUST Astro Carnival, 2014

2nd Prize, Charupath Art Exhibition, 2011

Projects

Acado: Webapp for creating, previewing, and exporting academic assignments with APA-7 format (HTML, TailwindCSS, NextJS, Vite, jsPDF, html2canvas)

MizuCV: Online CV builder for creating and exporting CVs (HTML, TailwindCSS, NextJS, Vite, jsPDF, html2canvas)

BRACU Course-to-Routine Builder: Real-time course section comparison tool for students (HTML, TailwindCSS, JS)

Mux Social: Open social networking platform without external interference (HTML, TailwindCSS, NextJS, PostgreSQL, Neon DB, Vercel Blob)

Disorder: Anonymous peer-to-peer chat and file-sharing platform with no persistent storage (HTML, TailwindCSS, PeerJS)

Goofy Gunners: 3D action multiplayer combat sandbox (Roblox Studio, Lua)

Phocheton/SecHero: Android app for checking device security integrity, app permissions, and diagnostic info. (Kotlin, Jetpack-Compose)

Mux Repeat: Automation recorder for keyboard and mouse input and can repeat them continuously (Python, Pynput)

Drone Zone: Simple survival game about Boids simulation and bees (C, SDL2)

JackBus: Track buses of Metrobus St. John's in real-time to decide the fastest route (HTML, CSS, LeafletJS)

Dolly: Multi-modal and multipurpose Discord bot, inspired by MEE6, Dank Memer and many more (NodeJS)

MandelEx: Fractal visualizer in real-time (Java)

Pcryt: LFSR-based encryption in Base64 (Python)